so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist today what I want to
do is share with you a topic that
doesn't get nearly enough attention in
the work of culture design and that is
group facilitation processes it turns
out that there's a lot that's now known
about how to organize and manage groups
how to design events and how to help
people move through decision-making
processes in order to creatively address
real-world problems in real time and the
book that I want to share with you today
is this one the change handbook the
definitive resource on today's best
methods for engaging whole systems and
it's a delayed by otra in my Peggy
Holman Tom Devane and Stephen Katie what
the change handbook does that's so
wonderful is it provides you a reference
source of all of the most prominent and
effective methodologies for group
facilitation so if you want to change
the organizational culture at your
company or your nonprofit or in your
office if you want to bring together a
group of people and form a community and
then collectively solvable problem if
you want to manage conflict or stimulate
creativity or creatively brainstorm
discover what the problems and
challenges are among a group of people
or any of a number of other things that
pertain to the way that a group is
working or not working and how to move
them through their stuckness to places
of solutions actions empowerment healing
and so forth that you really need to
know how group facilitation works and so
the change handbook is probably the best
resource out there for understanding how
to manage and facilitate groups now this
can be everything from coming in and
doing strategic advising and guidance
for the board of an organization it
could be creating an event like a
conference or an unconference and it
could be a something like taking a group
of people that have worked together for
a long time and helping them
re-establish and regram themselves and
work through the kinks so this book is
fantastic because not only does it go
through all of the major what
are called social technologies or user
experience design protocols for
facilitating groups but it tells you
when they're most useful to be applied
in which situations they're not useful
for so this includes things like open
space or unconference it includes things
like consensus building it includes
things like values alignment open
brainstorming and so on so all of these
are different technologies or
methodologies for guiding groups through
a process to achieve some purpose or
goal which culture design is all about
doing this so if you want to understand
what skills you should learn so that you
can do this effectively then this is the
book to get the change Handbook which is
a very very useful well-written
compendium of the best group
facilitation techniques in the world so
that's it I recommend you go and get
your own copy today keep it on your
shelf and pull it out anytime you need
it to just learn about in different
methodology start practicing those
different methodologies in your own
groups or in your organization's and
make the world a better place so there
you have it the change handbook one of
the best books for a group facilitation
out there enjoy